Finding Aid for the Jean Renoir Papers PASC.0105
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Part I - Production Files
  - Series IV: PROJECTS, including some not by Jean Renoir
    - CHRISTINE
      - - Manuscript notes: 10 pages, 29 pages, 10 pages, 10 pages, 43 pages, 9 pages, 4 pages, n.d. (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - LE CIEL ET LA TERRE
      - - Handwritten drafts: 20 pages, Aug. 6, 1970. - 5 pages, n.d. - 3 pages, n.d. - 5 pages, n.d. - 4 pages, n.d. - Typed story treatment, 13 pages. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - - Handwritten pages, 26 total. - Typed pages, 7 total [possibly dating from 8/29/70]. - Clipping "The Birth of the Solar System," Los Angeles Times, 1970. (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - - Annotated typed pages, 16 pages, 9/11/70. (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - - Annotated typed pages (2 copies) 32 pages and 37 pages, dated 10/23/71 through 12/11/71. - "La Vieillese," fragment, 7 pages, 12/9/71. - Miscellaneous typed, annotated pages, dated from 12/9/71 through 6/30/72, 12 pages. (Box 41, Folder 4)
      - - Handwritten and typed pages, annotated, 13 pages, dated November 10, [1970?]. (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - - Interleafed handwritten and typed pages, annotated, 50 pages total. n.d. (Box 41, Folder 6)
      - - Interleafed handwritten and typescript pages, annotated, 54 pages, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - - Interleafed handwritten and typed pages, annotated, 61 pages, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - - Handwritten pages, 19 pages, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - - Annotated typed pages, 13 pages, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - - Annotated typed pages, 27 pages, dated 11/9/71 through 7/5/72. (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - LE CINEMA AU SERVICE DE L'ENFANCE ANORMALE
      - - Typed notes, 17 pages, 6/12/36. (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - LES CONTES DE PERRAULT (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - Receipt for the deposit of the scenario by Pierre Lestringuez, 1/17/25. (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - LES COURTISANS
      - - Handwritten treatment, 4 pages, n.d. - Handwritten notes, 8 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - LE COUSIN DE GERSHWIN
      - - Legal pad with handwritten notes, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - LA CREATION DU MONDE
      - - Handwritten notes from a notebook, 22 pages, n.d. - Annotated typed pages, 4 and 6 pages, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - LA CROIX DE MALTE
      - - Handwritten notes in notebook, 42 pages, n.d. Treatment, 8 pages, 2 copies, 4/28/63. (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - LA DANSE MACABRE
      - - Handwritten pages, 7 pages, 5/8/68. (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - LE DELUGE
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, dated November 1947 (also includes commencement of additional project, "Les Ours en Cage," dated 11/28/47). - Handwritten pages, 130 pages, n.d. (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - - Handwritten notes, 8 pages and 38 pages, dated November 4-13, 1945, entitled "La Tour." - Handwritten notes [Dido Freire Renoir's hand], incl. "liste du personnages," 11 pages. - Magazine clipping, 11/30/47. (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - LES DEMI-REVES
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes [first 10 pages nearly completely excised], n.d. (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - DON JUAN
      - - Notes, handwritten, 4 pages, n.d. - Notes, typed, 3 pages (2 copies), n.d. - Script fragments, typed, 11 pages (2 copies), n.d. - Script fragment, handwritten, 7 pages, n.d. - Budget figures, handwritten, 7 pages. (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - EDMUND'S APPLE (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - Annotated typed screenplay, in English, by Joseph Steck (story by J.R., Michael Parks, David Wheeler and Joseph Steck), 68 pages, n.d.- 2 pages with sketches. (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - L'EDUCATION DES FILLES
      - - Four notebooks with handwritten notes, dated 12/1/56. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - EN AVANT ROSALIE
      - - Annotated treatment, 27 pages and 1-page "synopsis" (2 copies), 1967. (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - - Story treatment, 15 pages, n.d. - Treatment, 29 pages and 1-page prefatory note. (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - - Handwritten pages, 42 pages, c. 1967-1969. - 4 pages, handwritten notes. (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - - Story treatment, carbon copy, 15 pages, 7/22/67. - Handwritten pages, 60 and 6 pages, 7/22/67. - Typed, handwritten, and carbon versions of poem "Rosalie", 2 pages each, n.d. - Typed poem, carbon, and notes, 12 pages. - Notes, 20 pages, 4/19/67. (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - LES EXILES (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - Outline of the film by Kent MacKenzie, which J.R. attempted to distribute, 7 pages, typed, annotated, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - LA FAIM
      - - Annotated treatment, "Projet de film de Jean Renoir inspire du roman de Knut Hamsun," 25 pages, 7/6/61. - Xerox copy, with annotations and corrections, dated 5.8.61. - Treatment, 3 pages, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - - Annotated treatment, entitled "Yladjali" [or "Hyladjali"], 21+2 pages, 5 copies. - 2 carbon copies of "Hyladjali," 20+2 pages, 1960-1962. (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - LE FEU AUX POUDRES
      - - Scenario and receipt for deposit with Association des Auteurs de Films, 10/26/55. (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - - English translation of story line/synopsis, 12 pages (5 copies), 10/14/55. - French version, 15 pages (3 copies), 10/14/55. - Scenario, 15 pages (2 copies), n.d. - Scenario, 9 pages, n.d. - Location breakdown, 5 and 6 pages, n.d. (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - FIRST LOVE
      - - Typescript of film proposal and story outline by J. R. and Hugh Gray (2 copies), 23 pages, Los Angeles, 2/11/61. - "Renoir Film: Suggested Screen Treatment" by Travis Bogard based on J.R./Hugh Gray story outline, 20 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - FLORA
      - - Annotated typed pages, 10 pages, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - LES FRANCAIS
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, n.d. - Side-spiralbound notebook with handwritten notes, inside front page marked "Les Francais," n.d. - Handwritten pages, 19 pages, total, dated, 6/29-6/30 [no year]. - Handwritten pages, 21 pages, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - FRENCH REVUE
      - - Story outline, in English, with accompanying receipt for registration w/ Screen Writers' Guild, 8 pages (2 copies), 3/31/53. (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - FUGUES
      - - Annotated treatment, 11 pages, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - GABIN, JEAN
      - - "Notes pour le film de Jean Gabin." - Project synopsis, 1 page (2 copies), 3/19/43. - Project scenario, 11 pages (2 copies), 3/24/43. - "Notes..," 2 pages (2 copies), 3/26/43. - "Suite de la partie dictee.." 3 pages (2 copies) 3/27/43. (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - LA GLANDE DESTRUCTRICE
      - - Typed pages, 3 pages, 1 original and 1 copy, 2/12/74. (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - LA GRACE
      - - Pages from a notebook, 4 pages, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - LA GRANDE CUISINE
      - - Script fragments, 5 and 4 pages, n.d. - Handwritten pages, 2 pages, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - LA GUERRE ET APRES
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 17)
    - LE HEROS
      - - Typed pages, 1 original and 1 carbon copy, 2 pages each, 9/21/74. (Box 42, Folder 18)
    - HISTOIRE D'ENFANTS
      - - Typed pages, 5 pages, incl. original and photocopy, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 19)
      - - Treatment by Robert Flaherty, 20 pages, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 20)
      - - Annotated and corrected typed pages, 7 pages, n.d. - Typed fragment, considerably annotated and reassembled, 6 pages, n.d. - Manuscript pages, 13-28, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 21)
      - - Typescript, annotated carbon copy, 120 pages total, dated 6/11/48. (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - - Annotated typescript plus inserted handwritten page corrections, entitled "La Fuite de Monsieur Holmsen", carbon copy, 141 pages, dated 6/11/48 through 6/26/48. (Box 43, Folder 2)
      - - Annotated script, in English, 148 pages, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - LES HORREURS DE LA GUERRE
      - - Scenario, 4 pages (2 copies), 1952. (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - HOW BEAUTIFUL WITH SHOES (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - Photocopied short story by Wilbur Daniel Steele, 11 pages, with accompanying correspondence from Jack Fields, 1 page, 2/2/68. (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - HUMEURS
      - - Handwritten notes, 26 pages, n.d. (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - IDA
      - - Scenario, 43 pages, 8/8/35-8/28/35. (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - LES IMAGINAIRES (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - Play in three acts by Pierre Lestringuez, 111 pages, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - JUDGE NOT (not bu Jean Renoir)
      - - Synopsis from the publisher of the story by Sholem Asch, in English, 2 pages, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - JUDITH
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, 8/22/56. - Handwritten notes, 6 pages, n.d. - Clipping, "Terrorism Clouds Tlemcen, the 'Pearl of North Africa,'" New York Times, 7/26/56. (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - LE JUGEMENT DERNIER
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - LE JUGEMENT KANGOUROU
      - - Handwritten pages, 11 pages, August 1957. - Clippings from the San Francisco Chronicle, incl. "Peninsula Jail 'Court' Kills Inmate," 7/29/57. (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - JULES LE CONFORMISTE
      - - Handwritten notes, 13 pages, 36 pages, 21 pages, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - JULIE
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, 11/26/56. (Box 44, Folder 3)
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 4)
      - - Annotated scenario, typed original and carbon copy, 32 pages each, n.d. - Handwritten notes, 2 pages, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 5)
      - - Typescript, 164 pages, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 6)
      - - Typescript, carbon copy, 164 pages, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 7)
      - - Typescript, carbon copy, 164 pages, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 8)
      - - Bound script, cover marked "copy 1 exemplaire Jean Renoir." Depose a la Societe des Auteurs. 174 pages, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 9)
      - - Bound script, copy 2. Depose a la Societe des Auteurs. 174 pp, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - - Bound script, 174 pages, copy 3, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - - Bound script, copy 4, 174 pages, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - - Translated from the French by Mary Louise Gradwohl. Two copies: original typescript and xerox copy (both marked "no. 7733" on cover), in English, 164 pages each, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 3)
      - - Typescript, translated from the French by Mary Louise Gradwohl: carbon copy and bound xerox copy (both marked "no. 7737"), 164 pages each, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 4)
      - - Story outline, 24 pages, with annotations, and copy, n.d. (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - L'OR DU CRISTOBAL
      - - Postal receipt and copy of cover letter for scenario's submission to Association des Auteurs de Films, 2 items, 2/15/39. - Letter of acknowledgment and proof of receipt, 2 items, 2/20/39. (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - LANCELOT
      - - Handwritten pages, 70 pages, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 1)
      - - Notebook with handwritten notes, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 2)
      - - Treatments, drafts, and notes, typed 10/79-11/79, 143 pages total. Includes: Acts I and II (2 copies each) 56 pages, 10/27/79. - "Projet de scene pour Lancelot," (2 copies), 28 pages, 11/79. - Treatment, 58 pages, 11/23/79. (Box 46, Folder 3)
      - - Script, "Lancelot, piece en deux actes," 59 pages, typed 11/23/79. (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - LES LETTRES D'UN MILLIONAIRE
      - - Composition book, "Le Journal d'un Millionaire," c. 1/15/41. - Typed originals and copies, 34 pages, 1/41-5/46. (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - LE LEVER DU RIDEAU
      - - Typescript treatment by J.R. from a story by Vladimir Pozner, annotated/reassembled original, 12 pages, 1963. - Xerox, 17 pages, 1963. - Treatment, 7 pages, 10/26/63. (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - LOS ANGELES
      - - Notes, 18 pages, 5/21/45-5/24/45. (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - LOVE
      - - Notes, 7 pages, 11/1/46. (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - LUCIE
      - - Two notebooks with handwritten notes, one marked "Lucie" and "L. Doynal", n.d. - Notebook, marked "Lulu," and "Resume du 2 janvier au milieu de cahier" across cover, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - MADAME BOVARY A REBOURS
      - - Story synopsis (in English) 3 pages, n.d. - Script fragment for a remake, in English (2 copies), 16 pages total, n.d. - Collected script fragments on typing carbons, 220 pages, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 10)
      - - Two treatments by J.R. for remake/adaptation, one mimeograph/offprint, one xerox, 15 pages each, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - MAGNIFICAT
      - - Receipts for the deposit of the manuscript, 8/19/40, 11/12/59, and 12/28/59. - Project outline, 3 pages (4 copies), n.d. - 1941 version of project outline and scenario, 30 pages, 10/14/41. - Clipping, L.A. Times, 4/19/53. - Character list. (Box 46, Folder 12)
      - - Character sketches, in English, 7 carbon pages, 4/2/53. - Annotated treatment, in English, 43 carbon pages, 4/2/53. - Annotated treatments, 51 pages, n.d. (2 copies w/cover letter, 1 carbon copy, 1 xerox copy). - Notes, 2 pages. (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - LA MAISON DU DIABLE
      - - Notebook pages with handwritten notes (excerpt from notebook), 19 and 1 page, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - LA MALADIE
      - - Typescript notes, 4 pages, n.d. (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - MARCEAU ET LA LUNE
      - - Scenario, 9 pages (2 copies), n.d. - Handwritten pages, 4 pages, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - MAROUF THE COBBLER OF CAIRO
      - - Outlines, undated, 149 pages total: -"Tentative Construction Plan," typing carbons, 14 pgs. - "Prologue" outline, 330 pgs. - Story outline, 36 pgs (2 copies). - Additional story outline, 18 (nonsequential) pages. - Notes, 2 pgs, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - LE MASQUE
      - - Story outline, 1 page, 12/6/52. (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - THE MEAL ON THE MOUNTAIN
      - - Partial typescript, in English, 2 copies, 40 and 39 pages, 9/6/49. - Handwritten pages, 9 pages and 1 typed cover page, 9/6/49. (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - - Notes (3 copies), 15 pages, 9/27/49. - Treatment for Chapter One (3 copies), 9 pages, n.d. - Treatment for Chapter Three, 2 pages. - Handwritten notes, 14 pages, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - LA MEGRE APPRIVOISEE
      - - Notes, 12 pages, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - LES MILLIONS
      - - Handwritten pages, 7 pages, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - - Receipt for deposit of the manuscript, 5/11/38. - Photocopied pages of 1938 story outline, 32 pgs, 5/9/38. - Handwritten notes, 4 pgs, n.d. - Photocopied scenario, 4 pgs, 3/24/38. - Handwritten notes, 62 pgs, n.d. - Script fragments, 39 pgs, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - MIRACLE
      - - Five notebooks with handwritten notes, December 31, 1959 - February 5, 1960. (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - MON ONCLE LEANDER
      - - Handwritten notes, 9 pages, n.d. - Typed notes, 3 pages, 11/4/66. - Story outline, 11 pages, 9/15/66. (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - THE MONEY-CHANGERS
      - - Synopsis in French, 2 pages (2 copies), 4/8/46. - Story outline, entitled "Marie Madeleine," 9 pages, 6/20/46. - Story synopsis, annotated, in English, 29 pages (4 copies), 9/12/46. (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - - Treatment in French, 7 pgs. n.d. - Treatment in English, 22 pgs, n.d. - Synopsis, 10 pgs, 8/9/46. - Lists of characters, 5 pgs, 8/10 - 8/15/46. - General notes, 3 pgs, 8/12/46. - Prologue ("Peter's Millions"), 29 pgs, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - LA MORT SATISFAITE
      - - Annotated treatment, original and photocopy w/different annotations, 48 pages each, n.d. - Handwritten pages, 69 pages, dated 1965. - Clipping, "Woman Whose Heart Burst Is Recovering," Los Angeles Times, 8/1/65. (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - "MUSICAL"
      - - "Outline For A Musical," typescript in English, 29 pages (2 copies), n.d. (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - L'OMBRE DES PLATANES
      - - Typed pages, 2 pages (2 copies), dated 10/12 [no year]. (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - PARIS-PROVINCE
      - - "Gisele: Inspiration pour un film": typescript, original and carbon copy, 12 pages each, n.d. - Photocopy, 15 pages. - Cahiers du Cinema article, 9 pages, publ. 1954. - Handwritten pages, "Contes du printemps," 8 pages, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 19)
      - - "Paris-Provence: inspiration pour un film," in Cahiers du Cinema, no. 35, May 1954, pp. 2-13. (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - LE PARURE D'EMERAUDES
      - - Photocopied scenario, 6 pages, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - LA PEAU DE CHAGRIN
      - - Scenario, 7 pages (2 copies), n.d. - Scenario, 14 pages (2 copies), n.d. (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - PEDRO
      - - "Resume d'un scenario", 5 pages, carbon typescript and photocopy, 4/17/34. - Script fragment: typescript and annotated carbon copy, 20 pgs each, n.d. - Script fragment, typescript and carbon copy, 3 pgs each, n.d. - Handwritten notes, 9 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - LA PETITE FILLE DU ROI DE PRUSSE
      - - Story outline (2 copies) 3 pages, n.d. - Notes, 4 typed pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 3)
      - - Handwritten notes, 6 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - PROJECT DE PIECE EN UN ACTE
      - - "Projet de piece en un acte", 4 pages, 7/18/34 (2 copies). - "2eme fois", 5 pages, 7/19/34 (2 copies). - "3eme fois", 6 pages each, 7/20/34 (2 copies). (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - PIT BOY (not by Jeean Renoir)
      - - "Outline for film story of a pit boy and his pony" by Robert Flaherty, original and copy, 15 pages each, n.d. (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - PREMIER AMOUR
      - - Scenario "d'apres le roman de Tourgueniev [sic]," 3 pages (6 copies) w/attached cover letter from J.R., dated 6/25/52, and receipt of registration with Association des Auteur de Films, July 3, 1952. (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - PREVERT, JACQUES (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - "Scenario de Jacques Prevert," typescript, 162 pages, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - LE PRINCE ET LA CHANTEUSE DES RUES
      - - Letter and accompanying receipt confirming deposit of the manuscript (by J.R. and P. Lestringuez) with the Societe des Auteurs de Films, 5/18/26. 2 items total. (Box 48, Folder 32)
    - PROPOS SUR LE 'UKIYO-E'
      - - Typed notes, "Propose sur le 'ukiyo-e' (estampes japonaises) en film, 2 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 33)
    - QU'ELLE EST BELLE
      - - Fragment, 4 pages (pp. 9-12), n.d. (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - LE QUATORZE JUILLET
      - - Handwritten pages, 22 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - QUE DEVIENDRA CET ENFANT?
      - - Scenario, typescript and carbon copy, 8 pages each, plus 1 page of handwritten notes, 8/8/59. - Receipt for deposit of the manuscript with l'Association des Auteurs de Films, 8/14/59. (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - QUENTIN DURWARD
      - - Story outline, 13 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - REFLECT
      - - Carbon of letter applying for copyright, 9/17/26. - 2 receipts for deposit of scenario co-authored by Pierre Lestringuez and Jean Renoir, September 1926. - Personal "receipt"/note confirming transaction, dated 9/17/26. 4 items total. (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - LE REPAS
      - - Handwritten story outline, 3 pages, n.d. - Second version, 6 pages, no date. - Handwritten draft, 26 pages, n.d. - Handwritten notes, 18 pages, n.d. - Typed story outline, original and carbon copy, 8 pages each, n.d. [1967?]. (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - LE REPENTANT
      - - Story outline, handwritten, 10 pages, n.d. - Handwritten draft, 39 pages, n.d. - Handwritten notes, 7 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - LA RETRAITE AUX FLAMBEAUSE
      - - Handwritten story outline, 6 pages, 8/12/65. - Handwritten outlines, 9 and 8 pages, respectively, n.d. - Handwritten pages, 28 pages total. (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - ROMEO ET JULIETTE
      - - Scenario, dated 5/29/39, original and copy, 2 pgs ea. - Treatment, 7 pgs, n.d. - "Rapport Sur Mon Prochain Film," June 1939, incl proposed budget, 12 pgs. - Xerox of annotated typescript/galley proofs (author unknown) re project, 11 pgs, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - LA ROUQUINE
      - - Xerox of story treatment, 11 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - SABINE
      - - Story notes, handwritten, 6 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - SAINT-EXUPERY, ANTOINE DE (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - "Scenario par Antoine de Saint Exupery," 9 pages, n.d. (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - SANS QUEUE NI TETE
      - - "Projet de saynetes pour un spectacle de television": annotated typescript, 45 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - LES SAUVETEURS
      - - Correspondence and receipt for the deposit of the scenario, 1/10/38. (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - LE SCHPOUNTZ
      - - Story summary, presentation: "Idees de Monsieur Koch (Le Schoupntz [sic])," typescript original and copy, 3 pages each, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - LA SEQUESTREE
      - - Story treatment, copy of typed original with corrections and annotations, 19 pages total, c.1936. Includes "Reflexions au sujet de [Andre Gide's] La Sequestree de Poitiers." (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - THE SINNER
      - - Scenario, subtitled "A Story of Mary Magdalen", typescript and copy, 37 pages each, n.d. - Receipt for deposit with the Screen Writer's Guild, Inc., 4/29/46. - "Opening Choices," 2 pages, n.d. - Sequence outline, 3 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - SMALL-TOWN SCANDAL
      - - Typescript, first draft of film scenario (in English), 133 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - LES SOEURS THOMAS
      - - Story draft for play, 7 typed pages, along with 2 sets of handwritten pages, 6 and 8 pages respectively, 2/4/51. - Typed notes with handwritten annotations, 2 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - SPARKE
      - - Handwritten notebook, marked "Sparke-1a cahier," 10 pages total, c. 1930's. (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - STORY OF MR. POLLY
      - - Handwritten notes on typing carbons (some typed notes on back), 7 pages, n.d. (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - SUR UN BANC (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - Story/treatment by Simon Gantillon. 10 pages plus handwritten cover letter dated 5/24/1981? (Box 48, Folder 28)
    - LE SYSTEM DU DR. GOUDRON ET DU PROFESSEUR PLUME
      - - Letter to Ginette Doynel outlining story, 12/28/66, original, 4 pages, and 4 copies. - 12/28/66 revision, 12 typed and handwritten pgs. - News clipping "Chasse a l'homme.." Le Figaro, 9/16/68, and 4 typed-transcript copies, 2 pgs each. (Box 48, Folder 29)
    - TA VUKE N'BONGO (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - Scenario (note by Dido Renoir: "pas de J.R."), d'apres le roman d'Andre Derrin. Mimeographed offprint and xerox, 10 pages each. 1931. (Box 48, Folder 30)
    - THE TEMPEST
      - - First draft continuity script, in English, subtitled "A Jean Renoir-Dudley Nichols Production," 79 pages, with corrections and annotations, 4/10/43. (Box 48, Folder 31)
      - - Second-draft continuity script, in English, 4/15/43. 113 pages, includes interleafed pages of typed amendations (in French with English translation) and handwritten corrections and annotations. (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - - Second-draft continuity script, in English, 4/15/43. 99 pages, includes interleafed typed pages of amendations and annotations. (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - LES TEMPS DES CERISES (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - "Project de synopsis pour le film des Vieux Travailleurs. I/7/37. Dreyfus", scenario, 6 pages. - (Also includes: "Aventures," scenario by Dreyfus: 21 typed pages plus 1 handwritten page of notes by J.R., n.d.) (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - THE TERROR
      - - Story treatment (in English) by J.R. and Charles O'Neill, 49 pgs, w/ cover letter to Walter F. Wanger/Universal, 7/10/46. - Story outline w/ character list, in English, n.d. - Follow-up proposal, "Marie Madeleine," 13 pgs + 1 pg, 6/28-6/29/46. (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - THREE ROOMS IN MANHATTAN
      - - Treatment, in English, from Georges Simenon novel, 32 pages, 2 copies, 5/6/57. (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - TIBI
      - - Three notebooks with handwritten notes and project sketches, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - - Synopsis, 3 versions marked Resume I, II, III, incl. originals and copies of varying pgs and 1-page character list. - Character list, 2 pgs. - "Prologue," orig. + copy, 4 pgs. ea. - Fragment, 7 pgs. - Notes, 12 pgs (2 ms). - " Artus", 11 pgs, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - LE TONNEAU DU CLERGYMAN (not by Jean Renoir)
      - - Scenario by Dido Freire. Mimeographed offprint, 6 pages, n.d. (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - A TRIP TO TILSIT